# Joseph B. Letizia

401 Main St • Metuchen NJ, 08840 • (201)638-5264 • Joe.Letizia@gmail.com

Seeking a position in...

# Software Engineering

Application development professional capable of implementing complex software solutions. 4 years of experience in all phases of the software development lifecycle. Especially interested in creating scalable systems with technology stacks such as Ruby on Rails.

### **Technical Skills**

Platforms: Windows, Linux, Mac OS

**Languages:** Ruby, SQL, C#, VB .Net, Javascript

RDBMS: Postgres, MS SQL

**Tools:** Sublime Text 2, Rails, Devise, Active Record, Git, Amazon S3, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery

# Professional Experience

## Software Engineer

Connotate Inc, New Brunswick NJ May 2012-Present

- Responsible for backend products and systems focused on automating the extraction of web data
- Designed, implemented, and tested REST and SOAP API to allow users to programmatically interact with extraction scheduler and data store.
- Investigated NoSql databases such as MongoDB and made proof of concepts, prototypes, and demos
  in order to create a new logging framework allowing the database to scale out operations horizontally.
- Encouraged and executed transition from SVN to git as well as drafted policy guidelines for code reviews, branching and merging, and releases.
- Upgraded and maintained customer facing web application written in ASP.Net & C#. Added jQuery to manipulate DOM and facilitate AJAX.

#### Technical Co-Founder

TicketScalpr, San Francisco CA December 2012-Present

- Creating portal for game day P2P ticket sales. Disrupting second hand ticket market by focusing on physical, day-of sales between brokers and fans.
- Implemented Rails powered JSON API to provide data to front end iOS application.
- Investigated and implemented caching and performance improvements to ensure stability during "game-day rush."
- Created a baseline of RSpec tests to cover basic functionality.

#### Creator

Self Employed - DossierWeb September 2012-Present

- Designed, implemented, and deployed Ruby(1.9.2) on Rails(3.2.11) application to automate a manual process dealing with job applications for graduating doctoral students applying to tenure track positions
- Implemented model specs using RSpec to ensure proper application functionality. Learned and applied Test Driven Development methodology. Currently implementing Cucumber tests for high-level integration testing.
- Used Twitter Bootstrap, ¡Query, and Javascript to allow for a rich front end experience.
- Currently implementing Backbone.js to maintain front end code under an MVC framework
- Deployed application to Heroku and backed with postgresql.

## **Application Development Analyst**

Hess Corporation, Woodbridge NJ March 2009-May 2012

- Developed Tank Management System, an ASP.net and C# application backed by MS SQL server to facilitate the management of tank rentals.
- Integrated JSON enabled third party grids to display data.
- Analyzed root cause of catastrophic failure in retail web-based oil ordering system impacting 50+ users with a revenue stream of \$1 MM+/day.
- Designed and implemented sub-system overhaul of retail system which restored and improved overall system performance.
- Created data-warehouse following star-schema to facilitate reporting of sales, inventory, and activity data.
- Developed ETL processes to keep analytical data up to date while preventing performance issues in transactional system.
- Interviewed intern and full-time entry level candidates to assess technical aptitude.

#### Education

## Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, New Jersey Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Class of 2009